So what is the difference between a recursive and iterative?
Recursive algorithms can be very space and efficient.
Each recursive call adds a new layer to the stack, which means that if you are, if your algorithm
recurs to a depth of end, it uses at least of and memory.
For this reason, it's often better to implement a recursive algorithm.
Iteratively, all recursive algorithms can be implemented iteratively, although.
Sometimes the code to do so is much more complex.
OK.
So.
In the left, on the left, we have.
Via a vile X equal to F1, F2, F3 and return F3.
So this is that a recursive F1 well will depend on F2 f3 and then the returning of F3 will result in
a calculation of F2 and F2 will result in calculation of EF one while iterative on the right.
We have a variable X and this variable was through the iteration.
It's a changing.
It would change it from one to two to three.
So this is the iteration we we have a space one space for a VAR X while on the left.
When we use recursion or recursive algorithms, we we have to make a lot of space.
So every time we are calling a function or need anything or need and new calculation, we are reserving
a new space in memory.
So.
You can structure your program to be tail recursive to make the compiler optimize and treat it as an
iterative call.
OK.
We have three functions.
Imagine that we have three functions A, B and C function A. Calls Function B and Function B calls function
C a function.
A return is the value of function B and Function B returns the value of function C.
The instructions can be classified as tail recursive call as the first and the top of of this picture
indicates.
So this is the thing.
If you don't need any valuable to store function and function, sorry.
If you don't have or you don't need any variable to store function A and function B.
Function C does not need to return to Function B. So this is the case in blow, so.
When you have a fight, you don't need any variable to store function a this function and function B.
Calling f b f of B calls F of C and F C returns.
C and the return when returning C do something.
When doing something, it will return.
And B So you just skip Function B and function A. And reduce the variable that A and have B and B.
OK, so this is a bit about a recursive versus iterative.
OK, don't worry.
If you don't understand these concepts in the next exercises, we are going to demonstrate that complexity
of a recursive and it.